WILLIAM CONNATSER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EMAIL: me@williamconnatser.com PORTFOLIO: williamconnatser.com GITHUB: github.com/WilliamConnatser LINKEDIN: linkedin.com/in/WilliamConnatser

SUMMARY

Hard-working Software Engineer who has been fascinated with technology since the pre-teen years. Channeling that natural interest and curiosity into a profession fuels my daily growth and ambition. Possesses a strong attention to detail, and the ability to work independently with little supervision.

PROJECTS

3/2021 npmis.com/package/pa-toolbox **PG Toolbox**

Spare time solo project

Node.JS | PostgreSQL | Mocha | Babel

- Suite of CLI utility scripts which assists programmers manage Postgres databases
- Promotes writing pure SQL instead of using knex or an ORM for learning purposes github.com/WilliamConnatser/pg-toolbox

9/2020 AdamsMansionRetreats.com **Adams Mansion**

One month solo project

NextJS | Serverless Functions | PostgreSQL

- Marketing and informational website with calendar functionality and an admin panel to keep track of availability and bookings
- Integrated with SendGrid API to send auto-generated emails when the user submits the Contact Us form and the Booking form

5/2019 ChallengeJS

ChallenaeJS.com

One month group project

React | Express | PostgreSQL | Auth0 - JavaScript coding challenge application

- Worked on all aspects of the stack
- Leveraged web workers to run arbitrary code client-side and run tests github.com/labs13-clone

4/2019 Stockly

stocklylandingpage.netlify.app

One week group project React | Express | PostgreSQL

- Leverages sentiment analysis to predict stock prices and view market data
- Solely responsible for the entire back-end
- Architected data caching to get around API limit restrictions github.com/lambda-stockly

SKILLS

Languages

HTML | CSS | Sass | LESS

JavaScript | Node.JS | TypeScript | Python

Front-end Frameworks

React | Vue

Back-end Frameworks

Express | NextJS | Apollo GraphQL

Diango | Flask

Databases

Microsoft SQL | PostgreSQL | SQLite MongoDB

Operations Management

Git | Linux | Docker | Kubernetes | Jenkins Let's Encrypt | PM2 | Nginx | SSH | VPS Netlify | Heroku | ZEIT

Computer Science

Data Structures | Algorithms | OOP

EDUCATION

02/2019 to 12/2019

Lambda School

Full Stack Web Development

- Procured extensive experience building full-stack web applications, learning computer science fundamentals, and working with team workflows

EXPERIENCE

1/2020 to Present Florida Blue

Jacksonville, FL

Associate IT Developer

- Architected and developed fullstack JavaScript, TypeScript and Node.JS applications which assisted employees with their day-to-day duties by generating reports efficiently, accurately, and beautifully
- Significantly contributed to enhancements and bug fixes to multiple applications which reliably automated business processes and made the company more efficient
- Worked with numerous associates on several projects simultaneously while maintaining solid communication across teams and consistently meeting deadlines
- Promoted from a contractor at Pro Unlimited LLC to an employee in August of 2020 with similar responsibilities and duties

1/2018 to 7/2019

WEC Land Services College Station, TX

Software Engineer / Title Examiner

- Architected and developed fullstack a web application which organized a large ranch's legal documents with JAvaScript, Node.JS and MongoDB
- Managed integration with a FTPaaS API
- Performed meticulous oil & gas title research to determine surface, mineral and royalty ownership of property